<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities generated-datetime="2012-06-08 10:06:19"><iati-activity xml:lang="en" default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" last-updated-datetime="2012-05-24 09:51:46"><reporting-org xml:lang="en" ref="LI" type="21">LEAD International</reporting-org><iati-identifier>GB-COH-4075590-CSCF554</iati-identifier><title xml:lang="en">Empowering Civil Society Organizations and Volunerable Communities in Pakistan for Effective Adaptation to Climate Change </title><description xml:lang="en" type="1">This project aims to increase the capacity of poor and vulnerable communities in Pakistan to implement climate change adaptations to protect their livelihoods and contribute to bottom-up policy development.   Training on climate change will result in CSOs and target communities having the required knowledge, skills and capacity to influence local, national and international decision making.  Development of LAPAs will ensure climate change policy reflects local perspectives, knowledge, needs and realities, with 30 locally relevant adaptation micro-projects leading to enhanced sustainable livelihoods. Through building a CSO climate change National Advocacy Network civil society will be able to contribute to climate change discourse and policy development. Links will also be made with Pakistani diaspora groups in the UK, raising their awareness of climate change and building links to project communities.</description><activity-status xml:lang="en" code="2">The project is being implemented </activity-status><activity-date type="start-actual" iso-date="2011-09-01" xml:lang="en">Start of the project</activity-date><activity-date type="end-planned" iso-date="2015-03-31" xml:lang="en"/><participating-org xml:lang="en" type="10" role="Funding">DFID</participating-org><participating-org xml:lang="en" type="21" role="Implementing">LEAD International and LEAD Pakistan</participating-org><recipient-country xml:lang="en" code="PK">Sindh and Punjab provinces of Pakistan</recipient-country><sector xml:lang="ur" code="41081"/><sector xml:lang="en" code="15150"/><sector xml:lang="ur" code="31120"/><budget type="2"><period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"/><period-start iso-date="2011-09-01"/><value value-date="2012-05-23" currency="GBP">463827</value></budget></iati-activity></iati-activities>
